Not have learned a lot about how we prepare for deployment Let's finally deploy and for that I will
use a hosting provider called Hiroko.
You can simply google for it.
You can get started with it for free.
It's a very popular one.
But let me also say that there are dozens hundreds thousands of hosting providers you could use and
it's impossible to cover them all.
So I will try my best to show you the general steps of the alignment and to explain how it works in
general.
So Hiroko is what I will use here and I will show you how to deploy to Iraq in detail.
I already created a count.
You can't do that by simply signing up again.
That is free.
But first of all let me explain what Hiroko is and how we generally work with these hosting providers
because we use a hosting provider here.
Hiroko is a hosting provider.
The alternative always is did you build your own computer and you set it up such that it is connected
to the Internet that you are exposed to right sports sense that people can send requests to your computer
which might be running in your room and debt is not a solution I recommend unless you really know what
you are doing.
I realize its very likely to be insecure not scalable at all.
If your app is doing really well then you will quickly need a new computer or a second computer a third
computer and it only gets more complex and expensive and therefore we typically use hosting providers
like Hiroko but also like AWOS For example there we take our code and we deploy it onto managed spaces
on their computers also often called word Chole servers and this means that these providers have very
large and powerful machines in their data centers and you typically dont rent an entire machine though
you could do that.
But apart on that machine.
So part of the hard drive and some resources which are then provisioned for your managed space and your
code runs totally separated from the average apps which might be running on the same computer on the
same server.
Your app runs separated from them and now you of course want to connect your app running on that virtual
servers with your users.
Now typically you don't directly connect your space on that machine to your servers though that is also
possible on some providers.
But instead a lot of providers manage a lot of the heavy lifting for you and they give you their own
managed service you could say in front of your server where you can conveniently add SSL interruption
compression logging or load balancing which means that when you have multiple Witchell servers because
you wrapped this really doing well and you need more resources that in such a case incoming requests
are sent to service with available capacities in an efficient way.
So that is all handled by so-called managed service which are typically invisible to you which you don't
configure but which are part of the hosting provider package you could say and you just use a nice user
interface provided by the hosting provider to set up how your app behaves.
Regarding SS L or regarding logging and so on.
Now this all runs in a private network which means that your own server and your code is not directly
exposed to the web but it's exposed to that managed server which then in turn talks to the web and they
offer to your users through a public server a gateway.
And dad essentially is like a door where requests can come in there and then forward it to your server
to your Worrel server.
And the responses are all the.
So this is how this works.
This is how most hosting providers work.
That is what happens behind the scenes.
Just important for you to know.
Not really a lot of stuff you have to do on that.
Now that is the behind the scenes stuff.
Now let me show you how Heroku works and how we can play with it.
And of course that's just one example.
You can use any hosting provider you want for your application.
The general way of deploying or code does not really change.