Let's first of all understand NPM a bit better.
It's notes package manager as you learn and in the end it's a Selye a command line interface.
We always used it from the command line from the terminal by running NPM and then some command mostly
NPM install in this course the idea behind packages or tools like NPM.
And every programming language has a similar concept you could say is that we might have some isolated
functionality some code that we wrote or did we came up with that does something useful.
Let's say it generates a random number.
Now we can use that in our web application but maybe we want to use it in other applications as well
because this isolated functionality does not depend on our business logic in the project we're creating.
Or maybe we want to share it with the public.
Well if we want to share it internally or externally we can put it into a package with the help of NPM.
You can use NPM not just to install packages but also to create and share packages through that NPM
repository which is a cloud service where you don't have to pay for where you can host package as you
created and does all the service where you will and you can fetch packages from with the NPM install
command.
So in this repository which is managed globally you'll find the essence of packages obviously and if
you now have some node project you can use any of that you can use any of those packages with the NPM
install command frood at school.
And that is how you add packages to your project.
No matter if that is a package shared by you and you can also have private repositories or private packages
on NPM.
By the way that is something you do have to pay for but you can always use public packages and share
packages with the public.
That's the idea behind NPM.
Now let's have a closer look at the official NPM repository page and Tia waybill commands.
We can use you can visit any IMJ US DOT com.
That is the official page of NPM.
And there you can search for packages.
For example we could search for express here which is of course a package we used the Express framework
and then you see all kinds of packages that kind of were found forward and maybe packages that use Express
Maybe all.
Of course the express package itself.
And if you click on that you find some quick docks you see the words that were released here.
So here you can see the different words.
You could install through NPM you can target a specific word.
And by the way by going to your terminal and there with NPM install you can choose to package that at
sign and then a specific work number.
For example we could choose $416 free by typing for 16 dot free.
And now we would install that word into our project if we select no word in the latest one is picked
by default.
That's just a little side note so we can see that word in history.
We can see which our package this dispatch relies on.
And these packages will be installed for you automatically when you install it expressed.
Yes.
So DS will also end up in node modules as will the dependencies of these packages and that is why you
quickly end up with a big node modules folder by the way because you have a lot of dependencies of dependencies
of dependencies.
You also see things like official home page.
The get tab repository so the repository where you can find the source code for this package and so
on.
So this is really useful.
Now if you want to learn more about the NPM command though so what else you can run besides install
or how you can configure install.
For example with dash dash save words dash dash save def to install up production or a development dependency.
If you want to learn more about that do the official docs are of course the right place there if you
dive in.
You can learn way more about NPM and diving deeply into that would really be beyond the scope of this
course because NPM creating and managing packages that is a topic on its own not closely related to
no changes to language just an additional feature you get for free.
So here you can learn way more about that and here on this page if you scroll down a bit further you'll
also see all the whaleboat commands you could run.
And then if you click on one of them for example on install you also see how you may use it.
So here you see a detailed instructions on how you may configure it for example that you can run it
in global mode to install a package on your system and not just in a project or that you can of course
also install it with the dash dash save flag save death or save prod which is the same as just dash
dash save in the end.
So there you see all the ways of configuring that are running that command in different ways.
And if you want to learn way more about that.
And for most cases you just need NPM installed dash dash save or dash dash save death or dash G.
But if you want to learn way more of course these official docs are the place to go.
It is worth pointing out that you all can get help here locally when you type NPM help here.
You also get instructions on the available commands you may run and you can also get help on a specific
command.
So if I run NPM install dash dash help here or just dash age.
Then I see how I may run this command and also which options I have to add additional flex.
However these are just the common options not all options for the full docs of course.
You should dive into the official documentation here.
The commands you can run here especially installing are one powerful thing.
NPM allows you to do.
You can add any package you want to your project and number important feature is that if you click on
using NPM here you can run scripts with NPM and dead and generally is related to that package deal Jason
file you get when you put a project under control of NPM what you do with help of d NPM in the command.
We also use Statten that course Dad will ask you a couple of questions and then give you a package of
Jason File which you can use to configure a project and there you can not only keep a list of your dependencies.
You can also add certain scripts and you can run these scripts either with NPM start to run the stars
script or NPM run and then any script name you configured in there.
And that is very powerful especially when it comes to using NPM and notorious to build projects.
It is something I can best show any re-act application.
We worked with in this course.
Here I am in that application and there if we had a look at that package dodgiest and fall you see that
scripts area and there you see a couple of scripts which you can run.
For example start with NPM start but that's a special case.
All our scripts with NPM run and then for example of build or eject and then these scripts are executed.
Now these scripts actually use a third party package.
So a dependency which was installed re-act scripts we see it here in the dependencies list and then
that dependency holds to code that will actually do something and that is the next step I will come
back to with no japes being able to run on your machine and not being limited to spinning up a web server.